{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jane Seymour","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Boleyn","Catherine Parr","Catherine Howard"],"question":"Who Was Henry VIII's Third Wife?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seneca the Younger","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Socrates"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Even while they teach, men learn'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"‎Vincent van Gogh","incorrectAnswers":["‎‎Edvard Munch","Peter Paul Rubens","‎Rembrandt van Rijn"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Cafe Terrace at Night\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venice ","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Beijing","Ulaanbaatar"],"question":"In Which City Is Marco Polo Airport?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Harry Truman","incorrectAnswers":["Richard Nixon","Barack Obama","Lyndon B. Johnson"],"question":"Which US president popularized the phrase 'the buck stops here' with a sign on his desk?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Suva","incorrectAnswers":["Bandar Seri Begawan","Dushanbe","Victoria"],"question":"What is the capital city of Fiji?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dix","incorrectAnswers":["Dez","Dieci","Noir"],"question":"What is the French word for 'ten'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"William Wyler","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Ben-Hur?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"127 Hours","incorrectAnswers":["The Summit","Everest","Touching the Void"],"question":"What is the name of the 2010 fact-based drama in which James Franco played a mountain climber who was pinned by a rock?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry V","incorrectAnswers":["Edward VIII","William II","Stephen"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1413-1422?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"William James","incorrectAnswers":["Heraclitus","G. W. F. Hegel","Protagoras"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Philosophy is at once the most sublime and the most trivial of human pursuits'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mongolia","incorrectAnswers":["Sri Lanka","Thailand","Vietnam"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Ulaanbaatar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Cob","incorrectAnswers":["Ned","Sorl","Dev"],"question":"What is a male swan called?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","China","Central America"],"question":"Where in the world are tomatoes originally from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"St. Ignatius Loyola","incorrectAnswers":["Pope Francis","St. Peter","St. Paul"],"question":"Which founder of the Jesuits was imprisoned on two occasions during the Spanish Inquisition?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Guillotine","incorrectAnswers":["Firing Squad","Fire","Dogs"],"question":"What was the instrument of execution during the \"Reign of Terror\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Chevrolet","incorrectAnswers":["Ford","Gmc","Pontiac"],"question":"What Make Of Car Did Don Mclean Drive To The Levy In American Pie?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Operation Overlord","incorrectAnswers":["Operation Barbarossa","Operation Torch","Operation Watchtower"],"question":"What was the code name of the Allied invasion of Normandy in 1944?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Brain","incorrectAnswers":["Lungs","Heart","Kidneys"],"question":"Meningitis affects the _________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"D. H. Lawrence","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Charles Dickens","G. K. Chesterton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Lady Chatterley's Lover'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"C. S. Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","Jack Vance","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Prince Caspian'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"La Haine","incorrectAnswers":["The Lives of Others","The Big Lebowski","Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: '24 hours in the lives of three young men the day after a violent riot.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Motorsports","incorrectAnswers":["Baseball","Horse Racing","American Football"],"question":"What sport would you associate with The Daytona 500?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Operation Torch","incorrectAnswers":["Operation Market Garden","Operation Blitz","Operation Enterprise"],"question":"What name was given to the Allied invasion of North Africa in 1942?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"On Her Majesty's Secret Service","incorrectAnswers":["Live and Let Die","Goldeneye","Dr. No"],"question":"Which James Bond Movie Is Set During The Christmas Period?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Namibia","incorrectAnswers":["Lesotho","Eswatini","Angola"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Botswana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Formula One","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby","Cricket","Tennis"],"question":"Monza & Silverstone Are Venues For Which Sport?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hawaii","incorrectAnswers":["Alaska","Puerto Rico","Guam"],"question":"Which U.S. territory was attacked 18 years before it became a state in 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Kenya","Sudan","Nigeria"],"question":"Casablanca is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Peru","Uruguay","Romania"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ru' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Brad Pitt","incorrectAnswers":["Matt Damon","Tom Hanks","Leonardo DiCaprio"],"question":"Who played Oakland A's general manager Billy Beane in the film 'Moneyball'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Joseph Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Adams","Brian Jones","George Michael"],"question":"Who founded Mormonism?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Morocco ","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","France","Brazil"],"question":"A Tagine Is A Dish That Originated In Which Country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Minestrone","incorrectAnswers":["Linguine","Tiramisu","Pesto"],"question":"Which of these is a thick Italian vegetable soup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Harrison Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Hamill","Brad Pitt","Pedro Pascal"],"question":"Which actor originally played the role of Han Solo in Star Wars?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sang Som Rum","incorrectAnswers":["Pitorro","Tuba","Port wine"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with Thailand?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"World Wildlife Fund","incorrectAnswers":["Duolingo","NBC","Mustang"],"question":"Which of these brands has a panda on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sombrero","incorrectAnswers":["Cowboy Hat","Fedora","Bowler Hat"],"question":"Which of these is a type of broad brimmed Mexican hat?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Amber","incorrectAnswers":["Acacia","Carob","Bees Wax"],"question":"What resin was used by Ancient Romans as jewelry?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tunisia","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Transylvania","Northern Ireland"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.tn' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Four Years","incorrectAnswers":["One Year","Nine Years","Seven Years"],"question":"How Long Was The American Civil War?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rupee","incorrectAnswers":["Dollar","Yen","Ren"],"question":"What is the currency of India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cow","incorrectAnswers":["A Vixen","A Ewe","A Worker"],"question":"What would you call a female rhinoceros?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Erode","incorrectAnswers":["Erupt","Elevate","Emanate"],"question":"What is the geological term meaning 'to wear away'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Austronesian","incorrectAnswers":["Koreanic","Kra–Dai","Japonic"],"question":"The language 'Sunda' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"No Country for Old Men","incorrectAnswers":["Hacksaw Ridge","Pulp Fiction","Aliens"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Violence and mayhem ensue after a man stumbles upon more than two million dollars.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Potassium","incorrectAnswers":["Uranium","Lead","Iron"],"question":"What metal that is so soft it can be cut with a knife?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jodie Foster","incorrectAnswers":["Frances Fisher","Rachel Weisz","Salma Hayek"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in films including The Silence of the Lambs and Contact?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Oasis","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Kaiser Chiefs","Jethro Tull"],"question":"Which English rock band formed in Manchester in 1991 released the song 'Don't Look Back in Anger'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Davey Jones's Locker","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Jacob's Locker","Bootstrap Bill's Locker","Harry Logan's Locker"],"question":"What's the resting place of those buried at sea? ","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"William the Conqueror","incorrectAnswers":["John Calvin","Alfred the Great","Arthur"],"question":"Who was the first Norman King of England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Legend of the Fifth Sun","incorrectAnswers":["The Creation of the Gods","The Eternal River","The Green Void"],"question":"What was the name of the Aztec creation myth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Indo-European","Kra–Dai"],"question":"The language 'Burmese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1987","incorrectAnswers":["1977","1982","1992"],"question":"In which year was the discovery of treatment for AIDS?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Inxs","incorrectAnswers":["Pendulum","The Wiggles","The Veronicas"],"question":"Who Had A Hit In 1991 With \"Bitter Tears\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"December","incorrectAnswers":["September","April","November"],"question":"In what month is Christmas observed?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Elton John"],"question":"Which musician has famously performed over 3,000 shows in their 'Never Ending Tour'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Colombia","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Honduras","Panama"],"question":"In which country is the city of Cali?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Frozen","incorrectAnswers":["Hot","Dead","Wet"],"question":"What does the prefix 'cryo-' indicate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"13","incorrectAnswers":["4","50","49"],"question":"How Many Colonies Signed The American Declaration Of Independence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Richard Harris","incorrectAnswers":["Sam Shepard","James Hong","Jon Bernthal"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone and Gladiator?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Prehensile","incorrectAnswers":["Persistent","Prophetic","Precipitous"],"question":"What is the word used for a type of tail that can grasp objects?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["France","Greece","Egypt"],"question":"Rome is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2010","incorrectAnswers":["2004","2006","2008"],"question":"In which year was Inception released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Macedonia","incorrectAnswers":["Costa Rica","Thailand","Turkey"],"question":"In which country is mastika a popular drink?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Havana","incorrectAnswers":["Santiago de Cuba","Camagüey","Matanzas"],"question":"What is the capital of Cuba?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lauryn Hill","incorrectAnswers":["Alicia Keys","Missy Elliott","Aaliyah"],"question":"In 1998, which member of The Fugees won the Best New Artist Grammy for her first solo album?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Gabon","incorrectAnswers":["Liberia","Seychelles","Saint Vincent and the Grenadines"],"question":"Libreville is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Say Anything...","incorrectAnswers":["The Adventures of Robin Hood","The Silence of the Lambs","The Treasure of the Sierra Madre"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Lloyd Dobler'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gustav Holst","incorrectAnswers":["Edward Elgar","Igor Stravinsky","Claude Debussy"],"question":"Who Composed \"The Planets\" Suite? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A herd","incorrectAnswers":["A pride","A sedge","A barren"],"question":"What is the word for a group of deer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"14 horizontal stripes of red and white, with a blue square in the top left containing a yellow crescent and star.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal horizontal bands of yellow green and red.","White with a large red disk in the center.","Blue with a red cross outlined in white extending to the edges."],"question":"What does the flag of Malaysia look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","Spotlight","The Green Mile"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'After his father goes missing, a professor finds himself in a search for the Holy Grail.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Alec Baldwin","incorrectAnswers":["Donald Sutherland","Gary Oldman","Sean Connery"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Departed and The Aviator?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"I Write Sins Not Tragedies\" by Panic! at the Disco","incorrectAnswers":["\"Yo Home to Bel-Air\"","\"All Star\" by Smash Mouth","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Oh, well imagine, as I'm pacing the pews in a church corridor.\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Caravaggio","incorrectAnswers":["‎Salvador Dalí","Michelangelo","Cassius Marcellus Coolidge"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Beheading of Saint John the Baptist\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Purple, Green, and Gold","incorrectAnswers":["Blue, White, and Red","Pink, White, and Purple","Yellow, Green, and Orange"],"question":"What are the traditional colors of Mardi Gras?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sudan","incorrectAnswers":["Senegal","Cameroon","Algeria"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Khartoum?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Tenzing Norgay","incorrectAnswers":["Sir Edmund Hillary","George Mallory","Reinhold Messner"],"question":"Who, with a Swiss team, came within 1,000 feet of the summit of Mount Everest in 1952 before reaching the summit in 1953?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Salmon","incorrectAnswers":["Tuna","Trout","Cod"],"question":"Atlantic __________ are able to leap 15 feet high.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nine","incorrectAnswers":["One","Two","Six"],"question":"How Many Crusades Were There?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"David Lean","incorrectAnswers":["Stanley Kubrick","Alfred Hitchcock","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Who directed the movie 'Lawrence of Arabia'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chesapeake Bay","incorrectAnswers":["Hudson Bay","Puget Sound","Narragansett Bay"],"question":"What bay splits Virginia's part of the Delmarva Peninsula from the mainland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Suprematism","incorrectAnswers":["post-impressionism","Italian Renaissance","Dutch Golden Age"],"question":"The painting \"Composition 8\" by Vasily Kandinsky is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Red Hot Chili Peppers","incorrectAnswers":["The Monkees","Black Flag","Journey"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'One Hot Minute'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Photography","incorrectAnswers":["Painting","Sculpture","Architecture"],"question":"Which of the following is NOT a type of art commonly associated with the Renaissance?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"An ace","incorrectAnswers":["A king","A two","A jack"],"question":"In the game of blackjack, if you are dealt a natural blackjack with only 2 cards, one of them always has to be what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Contained","incorrectAnswers":["Carried","Coastal","Careful"],"question":"For what does the \"C\" in \"SCUBA diving\" stand?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Hatchling","incorrectAnswers":["A Piglet","A Maggot","A Lamb"],"question":"What is the word for a young turtle?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Louis Daguerre","incorrectAnswers":["Isaac Newton","Guglielmo Marconi","Claude Monet"],"question":"Which influential artist and photographer is credited with the invention of the camera?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jack","incorrectAnswers":["A Drake","A Dog","A Hob"],"question":"What is the word for a male donkey?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"hours","incorrectAnswers":["days","minutes","nights"],"question":"The snail mates only once in its entire life. When it does mate, however, it may take as long as 12 _______ to consummate the act.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pyongyang","incorrectAnswers":["Bangui","Ouagadougou","Thimphu"],"question":"What is the capital city of North Korea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Finland","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Russia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Switzerland","Liechtenstein","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Monaco?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cheese","incorrectAnswers":["Chocolate","Ice Cream","Eggs"],"question":" What is the main ingredient of a traditional fondue?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New York Mets","incorrectAnswers":["New York Canadiens","New York A's","New York Braves"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in New York?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Surrealism","incorrectAnswers":["Impressionism","Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","Crystal Cubism"],"question":"The painting \"The Son of Man\" by René Magritte is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Macbeth'?","difficulty":"easy"},